<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extension Points on Azure Service Operator</title>
    <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extension Points on Azure Service Operator</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ARMResourceModifier</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/arm-resource-modifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/arm-resource-modifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ARMResourceModifier&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to modify the payload that will be sent to Azure Resource Manager (ARM) immediately before it is transmitted. This extension point is invoked after the standard resource conversion and validation, but before the HTTP request is made to ARM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is invoked during PUT and PATCH operations to ARM, giving the resource an opportunity to make last-minute adjustments to the ARM payload based on runtime conditions, Azure state, or complex business logic that cannot be expressed in the generated code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deleter</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/deleter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/deleter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Deleter&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to customize how the reconciler deletes them from Azure. This extension is invoked when a resource has a deletion timestamp in Kubernetes (indicating the user wants to delete it) and gives the resource control over the deletion process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called after Kubernetes marks the resource for deletion but before the standard ARM DELETE operation. This allows resources to perform cleanup, handle special deletion scenarios, or coordinate multiple deletion operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ErrorClassifier</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/error-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/error-classifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ErrorClassifier&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to customize how the reconciler classifies and responds to errors returned by Azure Resource Manager (ARM). This extension is invoked whenever an ARM API call returns an error, giving the resource a chance to determine whether the error is retryable, fatal, or requires special handling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called in the error handling path of all ARM operations (GET, PUT, PATCH, DELETE). Proper error classification is critical for determining reconciliation behavior and user feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importer</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/importer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/importer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Importer&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to customize their behavior during the import process when using &lt;code&gt;asoctl import&lt;/code&gt;. This extension is invoked when importing existing Azure resources into Kubernetes as ASO resources, giving resources the ability to skip import, modify the imported resource, or perform additional validation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called during the import workflow, after retrieving the resource from Azure but before writing it to a file. This allows resources to filter out unwanted resources or adjust the imported representation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubernetesSecretExporter</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/kubernetes-secret-exporter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/kubernetes-secret-exporter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;KubernetesSecretExporter&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to export secrets from Azure into Kubernetes Secret objects. This extension is invoked after a resource has been successfully created or updated in Azure, giving the resource the ability to retrieve sensitive data (like connection strings, keys, passwords) and make them available in Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called during the reconciliation process, after ARM operations succeed but before the Ready condition is marked successful. This ensures secrets are available before dependent resources try to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostReconciliationChecker</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/post-reconciliation-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/post-reconciliation-checker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;PostReconciliationChecker&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to perform validation or checks after ARM reconciliation completes successfully. This extension is invoked after Azure operations succeed but before the Ready condition is marked successful, giving resources the ability to defer the Ready status until additional conditions are met.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called at the end of the reconciliation process, after the resource has been successfully created or updated in Azure. It provides a final opportunity to verify that the resource is truly ready for use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreReconciliationChecker</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/pre-reconciliation-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/pre-reconciliation-checker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;PreReconciliationChecker&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to perform validation or checks before ARM reconciliation begins. This extension is invoked before sending any requests to Azure, giving resources the ability to block reconciliation until certain prerequisites are met.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called early in the reconciliation process, after basic claim/validation but before any ARM GET/PUT/PATCH operations. It provides an opportunity to ensure that conditions necessary for successful reconciliation are satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface-definition&#34;&gt;Interface Definition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/azure-service-operator/blob/main/v2/pkg/genruntime/extensions/prereconciliation_checker.go&#34;&gt;PreReconciliationChecker interface definition&lt;/a&gt; in the source code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreReconciliationOwnerChecker</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/pre-reconciliation-owner-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/pre-reconciliation-owner-checker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;PreReconciliationOwnerChecker&lt;/code&gt; is a specialized variant of &lt;code&gt;PreReconciliationChecker&lt;/code&gt; that validates only the owner&amp;rsquo;s state before reconciliation, without accessing the resource itself. This extension is invoked before any ARM operations, including GET requests on the resource being reconciled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The key difference from &lt;code&gt;PreReconciliationChecker&lt;/code&gt; is that this extension &lt;strong&gt;avoids&lt;/strong&gt; performing GET operations on the resource itself, only checking the parent/owner resource. This is critical for resources where the owner&amp;rsquo;s state can completely block access to the child resource.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SuccessfulCreationHandler</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/successful-creation-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/contributing/extension-points/successful-creation-handler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SuccessfulCreationHandler&lt;/code&gt; allows resources to perform custom logic immediately after they are successfully created in Azure for the first time. This extension is invoked once after the initial ARM PUT operation succeeds, giving resources the opportunity to capture information, set fields, or perform initialization that depends on the Azure-assigned resource ID.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interface is called after the resource exists in Azure and has been assigned an ID, but before subsequent reconciliations. It runs exactly once per resource, during its initial creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
