<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User’s Guide on Azure Service Operator</title>
    <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User’s Guide on Azure Service Operator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/annotations/</guid>
      <description>Annotations understood by the operator #  Annotations specified by the user #  Note that unless otherwise specified, allowed values are case sensitive and should be provided in lower case.
serviceoperator.azure.com/reconcile-policy #  Specifies the reconcile policy to use. Allowed values are:
 manage: The operator performs all actions as normal. This is the default if no annotation is specified. skip: All modification actions on the backing Azure resource are skipped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/authentication/</guid>
      <description>Authentication in Azure Service Operator v2 #  Azure Service Operator supports two different styles of authentication today.
 Service Principal aad-pod-identity authentication (managed identity)  Service Principal #  Prerequisites #   An existing Azure Service Principal.  To use Service Principal authentication, specify an aso-controller-settings secret with AZURE_CLIENT_ID and AZURE_CLIENT_SECRET set.
 AZURE_CLIENT_ID must be set to the Service Principal client ID. This will be a GUID. AZURE_CLIENT_SECRET must be set to the Service Principal client secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/conditions/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Conditions #  Each resource reports a Ready condition in .status.conditions. It is also visible when you examine the resource with kubectl get, for example:
$ kubectl get resourcegroups.resources.azure.com NAME READY SEVERITY REASON MESSAGE aso-sample-rg False Info Reconciling The resource is in the process of being reconciled by the operator If the condition&amp;rsquo;s status is True (visible in the READY column via kubectl get) the resource is in the goal state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/diagnosing-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/diagnosing-problems/</guid>
      <description>Diagnosing problems #  Common mistakes #  ASO controller pod in Status CreateContainerConfigError #  $ kubectl get pods -n azureserviceoperator-system NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE azureserviceoperator-controller-manager-69cbccd645-4s5wz 1/2 CreateContainerConfigError 0 7m49s Very likely that you forgot to create the aso-controller-settings secret. This secret must be in the same namespace as the pod.
You can confirm this with kubectl describe pod -n azureserviceoperator-system --selector control-plane=controller-manager. Look for the &amp;ldquo;Error: secret &amp;ldquo;aso-controller-settings&amp;rdquo; not found&amp;rdquo; event in the describe output:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/multitenant-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/multitenant-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Deploying Azure Service Operator v2 in multi-tenant mode #  The current release version of the Azure Service Operator (ASO) deployment YAML installs the operator in single-tenant mode: deployed in the azureserviceoperator-system namespace with a single set of Azure credentials, and manages resources in any namespace in the cluster. That single operator deployment handles webhooks fired when Azure resources are changed.
ASO may also be deployed in a multi-tenant configuration, enabling the use of separate credentials for managing resources in different Kubernetes namespaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/resources/</guid>
      <description>Supported Resources #  These are the resources with Azure Service Operator support committed to our main branch, grouped by the originating ARM service. (Newly supported resources will appear in this list prior to inclusion in any ASO release.)
authorization #  ARM version 2020-08-01-preview #   RoleAssignment (sample)  Use CRD version v1alpha1api20200801preview
batch #  ARM version 2021-01-01 #   BatchAccount (sample)  Use CRD version v1alpha1api20210101</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: CosmosDB to-do List</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/tutorial-cosmosdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/tutorial-cosmosdb/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial: CosmosDB to-do List #  Follow the guided example to create a to-do list application backed by CosmosDB. The CosmosDB is hosted in Azure but created easily via kubectl and Azure Service Operator!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: PostgreSQL Votes</title>
      <link>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/tutorial-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure.github.io/azure-service-operator/introduction/tutorial-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial: PostgreSQL Votes #  Follow the guided example to create a simple voting application backed by PostgreSQL. The PostgreSQL Server and Database are hosted in Azure but created easily via kubectl and Azure Service Operator!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
